iPhone Duo is a groundbreaking
new device,
offering unique capabilities,
while still feeling familiar.
When people use your app,
they expect it to feel at home
on the device they're using.
Other videos in this series show
how your app can have
a first-class experience
across devices.
We're going to show you how to take
advantage of the unique features
of iPhone Duo
to make your app truly magical.
I'm Chris Donegan,
an engineering manager
in UI Frameworks.
And I'm Alex Muller,
a system experience engineer.
You'll learn how
to respond to the hinge
to drive amazing interactions
and effects,
support rich workflows
with split view multitasking,
and leverage scene accessories
to show UI across multiple displays.
Let's open up with the hinge.
Opening iPhone Duo is stunning.
Notice how the wallpaper reacts
to the angle of the hinge
and applies a zoom effect.
Your app can respond
to the hinge as well.
SwiftUI provides
a new onHingeChange modifier,
and UIKit provides UIHingeInteraction.
Both give you access
to the high-level hinge status of:
closed, partially open,
and fully open.
Beyond the discrete status,
it provides continuous updates
of the hinge angle.
This is an app I've been working on.
It has a playable guitar
to level up my air guitar sessions.
I have an idea to use the hinge
to drive a pitch bend
like a whammy bar.
This is my Instrument view.
It has the pitch bend value as state,
which is passed to the guitar view
in the body.
I'll start my whammy feature
by adding the onHingeChange modifier
to the guitar view.
This modifier takes a closure
with two arguments:
the previous hinge context
and the current.
In this case,
I just need the current context.
Next, I check for a non-null hinge.
A null value indicates the app
is running on a device
without a hinge.
In addition to checking availability,
I'm also only interested in updates
when iPhone Duo is partially open.
I'll make sure to add
an else condition,
so the pitch bend is reset
when the app is not reading
the hinge angle.
Finally, I'll calculate the pitch bend
using the angle
and update the state.
Using the onHingeChange modifier,
my guitar app has
a new level of expressivity.
Hinge data is observed live,
and is ideal for driving
interactions or effects.
For layout, use the arrangement
and region APIs.
Check out "Strike a Pose with
Adaptive Layouts on iPhone Duo"
for more.
I'm really excited to see
creative ways in which apps use
the hinge.
I think they're really powerful.
Absolutely.
But iPhone Duo has so much more
up its sleeve.
iPhone Duo brings powerful
multitasking features
that your app
should be ready to handle.
All apps participate in multitasking
on iPhone Duo,
where two apps can be placed
in a side-by-side layout.
If your app already supports resizing
on iPad or iPhone Mirroring,
you're off to a great start.
iPhone Duo has
a completely new layout,
stacking video and apps together.
Your app handles both
of these layouts the same.
The system makes supporting
these layouts easy.
It provides tools like size classes
and scene geometry to use
in your layout decisions.
Follow best practices from
"Prepare your app for iPhone Duo."
iPhone Duo is the first iPhone
to support multiple instances
of your app's UI.
If your app supports this on iPad,
it will on iPhone Duo as well.
There is one thing to keep in mind.
On iPad, new windows
can be created at any time.
On the outer display of iPhone Duo,
new windows cannot be created.
That behavior is reserved
for the inner display.
This dynamic availability
is unique behavior to iPhone Duo.
Make sure you handle errors
when requesting new scenes.
Use UIWindowSceneActivationAction,
which automatically hides
when new windows aren't available.
If you're interested in adding support
for multiple scenes
for the first time,
check out the documentation.
Split view multitasking
is not the only way
to get multiple scenes in your app.
Scene accessories allow your app
to show content on multiple displays
at the same time.
For iPhone and iPad, scene accessories
give your app the ability
to pair additional content
with your app's main UI,
like using your iPhone as a controller
for a game on an external display.
The system dynamically controls
the availability of these accessories.
They are enabled by default,
but can be toggled at any time.
Respond to changes
of an accessory's availability
using observation tracking,
so your app stays perfectly in sync
as system conditions change.
New for camera apps on iPhone Duo,
CameraCaptureAccessory allows you
to pair additional UI
on the outer display,
while your app's main UI
stays on the inner display.
This lets you show content to a person
while taking their photo
or recording them.
The camera capture accessory
is available
when your app is full screen
on the inner display,
and your app has
an active camera session.
Register your accessory
on the same view as your camera UI.
Learn more about
the new camera features
in "Build a great camera experience
for iPhone Duo."
To prepare for this talk,
I've been building a camera app
to help us practice.
I want to show a teleprompter
on the outer display
to help us learn our lines.
To get started,
I use the sceneAccessory modifier
to add a camera capture accessory.
By adding the accessory
on the camera view,
the teleprompter will only be visible
when the camera view is visible.
And that's all the code I need.
Now, while the camera view
is on the inner display,
the teleprompter view
is shown on the outer display.
Next, I want to be able to practice
from memory,
and having a button to toggle
the teleprompter would help.
I add a toolbar with a button
that updates the enabled state
of my teleprompter model,
which is then given to
the camera capture accessory.
Next, I want to disable
the toolbar button
when the accessory is not available,
like when the device is closed.
Adding onAvailabilityChange modifier
to the camera capture accessory
gives me a callback
to observe this change.
And now we have
a full-featured rehearsal app
that takes advantage of both displays,
showing the teleprompter
only if we need it.
Thanks for putting that together.
It really helped me practice.
[aside] You needed it.
I hope we've sparked your creativity
to make your app magical
on iPhone Duo.
Update your app to support
split view multitasking,
use the Hinge API to build
impressive interactions and effects,
and adopt scene accessories
to have your app
span multiple displays.
And with that, we come to a close.
Thanks so much for tuning in.